

Software Engineer And Data Science

Details +62 822 3427 8915 ahmadreys@gmail.com Jember – Jawa Timur

Links

Web Portfolio

<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>Instagram</u> <u>Github</u>

Hobbies

- Football
- Badminton
- Reading
- Games

Languages

English Indonesian Intermediate Native

Profile

Hi I am a **Software Engineer** and **Data Engineer**. I've been worked more than 3 years as a **Software Engineer** in the **Banking and Mining Industry**. I am good at Software Development Using **Laravel Framework**, **React JS** and **React Native**. I love **Data Engineer** using **Microsoft SSIS**, **SSRS**, **SQL** and other tools. I'd like to improve my self and challenge to do something new. I am a fast learner and easy to adapt to a new environment.

Employment History

IT Staff, PT Cita Mineral Investindo (Harita Group) Tbk, Jakarta

July 2021 - Present

My role in this position as IT Staff that developed **ERP system** for company using **Laravel**, **React Native and PostgreSQL**. Beside it, I also support to other department to **maintain IT Infrastructure**. Develop **mobile application for HR Department** using **React Native** and **Laravel Lumen**.

- Developed ERP system for company using Laravel, React Native and PostgreSQL.
- Maintained ERP System from the entire process that users conduct and supported them to resolve the problem.
- Established Human Resources Information System (HRIS) that our team developed.
- Collected informations from users and analyze the requirements to improved or implemented to our project.
- Created some documents such as User Acceptance Testing (UAT), Manual Book, Flowchart.

ETL Developer, PT Bumi Amartha Teknologi Mandiri, Jakarta

October 2019 - October 2020

My role in this position as a **Regla Team**, actually implementation IFRS9 (International Financial Reporting Standard 9) in **PT BCA Multifinance**. In this project I **used SQL Server**, **Oracle DB for database and Microsoft SSIS** for the data flow process.

- Completed the International Financial Reporting System 9 (IFRS9) project at PT BCA
- Multifnance
- Improved some feature in the system, Using SQL Server, Oracle DB for database and Microsoft
- SSIS for the data flow process.
- Delivered some reportings in various format that users requested.
- Maintained system to proceed monthly reporting.
- Created documents such as Functional Specification Document (FSD) and Technical Specification Document (TSD)

Web Developer, PT Panca Prima, Surabaya

May 2019 - August 2019

My role is as a web developer to build **ERP applications** for real estate companies. Here I use **the laravel framework** to build the application.

Mobile Developer Intern, PT Itematik Pramitha Nusantara, Yogyakarta

March 2019 - June 2019

My role in this position is to develop **point of sale (POS)** mobile apps.
Using **Flutter Framework** as front end mobile. **Laravel Framework** as Back End API to send data to UI.

Education

Bachelor Informatics Engineering, Politeknik Negeri Jember, Jember

September 2015 - July 2019

Software Engineering, SMK Negeri 8 Jember, Jember

June 2012 - June 2015

Personal Project

Sentiment Analysis On PT Kereta Api Indonesia Social Media, Jember

July 2018 - December 2018

Customer Sentiment On PT KAI Social Media.

NilaiGizi.com, Jember

June 2018 - September 2018

Information Of Product Nutrition Website.

AhliGizi.id, Jember

January 2018 - June 2018

A Nutrition Consultant Website Platform

Skills

Data Engineer & Data Science

I have experience work in data engineer especially as a ETL Developer Using Microsof SSIS, SSRS, SQL Server and Oracle DB. I have learn about Hive, Spark, Hadoop from Cloudera to organize data. And I have learnt how to use NoSQL db using CouchDB and MongoDB. I have done my research about sentiment analysis on PT Kereta Api Indonesia Twitter account using Python, Pandas. I have learned how to use Tableau, Microsoft Excel and Power BI to Analyze data.

Web Development

I have worked on some project as a web developer using **Laravel**, **Code Igniter**, **and Vue**. Actually in web development using some programming language such as **HTML**, **PHP**, **Javascript and Mysql**. In web development I have worked on some database to save data using **Mysql**, **SQL Server and PostgreSQL**.

Mobile Development

I have experience to develop mobile application using **React Native and Flutter**.

Design

In my spare time I like to use my time to design UI/UX such as **Mobile Apps, Website, and Social Media**. I usually use **Adobe Photoshop, Adobe XD and Figma to design**.

Certifications

Desktop Application Training Professional Level, e-biz Microsoft Partner

December 2018

Database Administrator, BNSP

October 2018

Test Of English for International Proficiency, Ednovation International

July 2019

Courses

SQL Fundamentals - Data Analyst, DataCamp

January 2023

Data Analyst, Ministry of Communication and Information Technology (Indonesia)

October 2022

The Data Science Course Bootcamp 2020, Udemy

November 2020

Business Sentiment Analysis Using Python, Data Science Indonesia

September 2018

Competitions

Kamadjaja Hackathon Day, Kamadjaja Logistics - Surabaya

November 2018

Coding Competition, Politeknik Negeri Jember

October 2018

Google Firebase AppFest Hackathon 2017 Indonesia, Google - Jakarta

September 2017

Gerakan Nasional 1000 StartUp, Kominfo - Surabaya

August 2017